hello YouTube
I am by myself today as far as on video
goes hopefully someone will be watching
soon and can let me know if the sound
was working I did test it as best I
could
with technology before coming in stream
yard Bentley isn't joining me today
because he had life events come up as
happens that's one of the reasons we
want to grow this board this group of
people that is committed to creating the
tech cooperative so that when life comes
up there the project doesn't stop right
they the entity this does kind of stop
the project because there's two of us so
in 50% of us aren't here clearly quorum
as it met I put a call out taking be
people and as well as just Twitter and
periscope in general for people to come
and join to see if they wanted to join
on camera there was more interest in
joining the viewership and commenting so
we're gonna see how this works this is
what I did for the first month that I
did these things at this time before
Bentley joined me and it is not as easy
for me as being part of a conversation
because a lot of times I have to like
guess into what people are asking or
actually saying when they're when
they're typing things out but I'm going
to do it to the best of my ability on
that I'm capable of showing up on today
so we're creating a tech cooperative I
released a video series just over a
month ago explaining the why why a tech
cooperative as power is important and
basically you don't want to watch half
an hour videos it is that technology is
powerful we have a handful of companies
with a lot of data and a lot of money
starting to change our laws and our
politics even technology is powerful
we're having this conversation on
technology technology is also risky it
to come up with a new idea hey Colleen
and put it out into the world comes up
with it a lot of risk especially if
you're doing it in I wanna say secret
but that's not quite the right word when
you're doing it in the normal
conventional capitalist way we're like
you're coming up with an idea and then
releasing it onto the market it's risky
you spend a lot of money and a lot of
time creating it and then chances are
it's not going to go anywhere and then
your failure means future people also
already have something working against
them where's all the customers that
signed up for your technology or gonna
be less likely to sign up for technology
in the future so technology's powerful
technology is risky but together
technology's more powerful because we
can trust in it and we can create it in
a way that we trust it we can create it
in a way that it's transparent and that
it has it empowers us without being
empowered over us in doing so we also
can make it less risky when we share in
the cost when we share in the ingenuity
when we decide to come together and
create something that we already know we
want that is what together tech is
trying to do is figuring out how do we
create how do we collaborate to create a
collaboration platform once we have the
collaboration platform how do we
continually improve it and how do we
also use it to empower all the
individuals to create their projects so
we have our project raising our second
one is tomorrow on Saturdays on this
channel two hours before this thing
starts so like right now is 11 a.m. my
time we start them at nine am we last
week we raised we collections my brother
Adrian's project and this week we are
raising J cousins project call all all
being home and there's a link in
description as to what that is in the
description box of that video so that is
the idea Cafe this and that are what I
am doing to create game be to create a
world that works for me in a world that
works for everyone
I see technologies a very powerful tool
that we can use to do everything at once
no one person can hold all the
information no one person can do all of
the things that need to be done
simultaneously on this planet to correct
a lot of the stuff that we as a species
have done to this planet each other
ourselves but collectively we can if we
just take on what we have ownership of
to us and were empowered with the tools
to be able to more effectively take on
that work so if you have an idea you can
go and get people to work on it if it
resonates with them if you have a
problem we can crowdsource a solution
and creating that platform is what what
we are focused on but what I'm currently
struggling with and maybe people can
help me out here is the idea Cafe
doesn't struggle to get people when I
host one for that we enjoy the
conversation people are just showing up
for a conversation around a question
right now we're only hosting them for
game because that's just my world and
what I want to talk about whenever I try
to put it out to the mental health
community or the autistic community or
the queer community there just isn't as
much interest in having one weekly and I
don't want to spend my spoons coming up
with a new a new group every every week
so I don't have problem getting people
to the idea cafe it looks like we also
don't have problems getting people to
the project raising it's a new project
every week and I don't know we're only
gonna be in our second week so maybe I
should wait to talk about maybe we will
have trouble both getting projects there
because there's more projects that we
have weeks to fulfill already and people
come and participate in it but this I
don't know how to get people not even to
come to this timeslot but like we need
to collaborate to create a collaboration
platform it can't be created in the
backend it without public view and then
release to the public and somehow be a
solution part of what we're doing the
project raising for is because we want
it we want to support all of these
amazing projects are coming from people
but also we want to find the common pain
like what is it that would help move
those projects forward so that we can
solve that problem together is it
funding is it marketing is it getting
people on board whether to work or like
whether it's customers or employees or
partners what what happens to be the
sticking point and then solving a lot of
those problems together that is the one
of the reasons I focused on technology
is that I know all of those sticking
points I'm a very low risk individual I
cannot take on risk find out
emotionally it just does not work so
well and so I have thought up a way
that's risk basically risk-free I mean
showing up here my egos on the line my
butt nothing else I don't have money on
the line there's no my time is here I am
I'm okay with this I'm okay with
sacrificing looking like an idiot
sacrificing getting it wrong on the path
to getting it right
and I'm looking for we are looking for
other people who also want to do that
not necessarily technology people not
people who know how to code because we
can pay those people we can crowd fun
and get employees on board what we need
is the passion and the ingenuity for
like what tech do we want and so the
question I posed to the game be space
this week that I thought would entice
people to come and maybe his that is
what would a platformer need to be a
collaboration platform so if Facebook
was designed for collaboration and for
actually getting projects out into the
world what would that look like but also
for you to participate in it what would
make it fun and exciting and part of
that also is we need a funding model our
current funding model that we've is like
people pay ten bucks a month into a pool
we vote on what we do with that money
creating the collaboration platform
itself and then we have a pool with
money to create all of the projects that
we want we vote on which one sort have
the most stem residents with us and
there's an infinite number of ways to do
that so what would make a collaboration
platform worth $10 a month to you what
would make you want to put in $10 a
month to get what it has to offer
I understand nobody is paying $10 lent
for Facebook that and we've already
gotten Facebook and it's free so that is
our level of integrity are also not
going to pay for Wikipedia we're not
going to pay for information because
it's already available even if we can
improve on it people generally aren't
going to pay that but people do pay and
there's a lot of tech out there that is
for project management that is for time
coordination that scheduling groups it's
doing that level and most of those
things cost $10 a month per person and
as a person involved in
of all or trying to be involved in
multiple projects there isn't a way for
me as an individual to keep those things
organized and that is a collaboration
platforms like project management meets
communication tool and scheduler and
also as a person I can go on and find a
project to work on as a person with a
project I can go on and find people to
to work on my project with me and so
that is the question I pose to all of
you which you'll have to type out
because that there's or if you would
like you can also join me here I'm just
gonna put this here even though no one's
going to type this out and unfortunately
I just make things clickable yet but if
you want to join me on camera you can
also it take the camera out and just be
a voice you can throw it to that that's
not really that long someone could
actually type that out I go but I think
the people watching are probably the
people who don't want to be on camera in
voice but it is you are welcome so what
Bentley and I were going to talk about
today was making this just like our
Saturday conversation has become a
project raising for other people's
projects where we are brainstorming how
to meet their aspirations right the
person brings their project tells us
what they want to get out of that hour
and we try we try to help them as best
we can that is what we are looking to do
here on Fridays is have people come and
be honorary temporary board members to
see is this something they want to
participate in but but more so like
you're not committing in any way you're
just showing up for that hour and
helping us move it forward offering
ideas and opinions on you know if we're
talking about funding that week what is
a funding model if we're talking about
the communication tool how do we how do
we collaborate on on that using existing
technology and creating the technology
that bridges the gap between what exists
like zum-zum exists and we can use it
and it's free for a certain number of
people if we can create this what we've
been talking about in these spaces is
the scheduling tool to get people to a
conversation then we
can like that is what what we were once
we have that then we can use zoom we
don't need to recreate video
conversations we can use what already
exists so that what we can create is
very beta and very cheap and then see
how do we improve it right how do we
continually improve it I'm just gonna
put your comment to pure Colleen knowing
what you're supporting is important in
funding yes no and that is like right
now Bentley and I are talking about well
well what is the word I wanna say token
but that's not quite right like we're
gonna be putting $20 a month in right
it's just me and him right now the idea
isn't that that $20 a month is really
gonna do anything it's that we Bentley
and I because were the only two members
at the moment are the ones who decide
what that money goes to right so in
third people the fourth person comes on
that that is part of the democracy the
the collaboration of what do we spend
those funds on we're not going to be
sending them on one-off projects that
aren't the tech cooperative right we're
not going to be spending them on cube
spawn as much as cube spawn is an
amazing project later on when we have
the collaboration platform and we have
in excess of money that is what we we
will then as a community vote on what's
our priority right as climate change our
priority great then what projects are
the best under climate change from the
best under food can getting us fed I
don't say food sovereignty I don't know
that's right and so it is that is a very
important piece is that if you don't
know what you're funding right like I'm
not giving $10 off the Facebook to
decide what they're going to what
they're gonna spend that money on but
since we not Bentley and I but we as in
the collective we of like whoever is a
member of it gets to just is the are the
ones putting in the money they're also
ones deciding where that money goes and
I was awesome why does my bring when I
talk about five things at once so I was
talking with with Jasper Skye this last
week about fractal democracy and the
idea that you get seven people together
and in every level it's 7 to the power
of whatever level that is so that was a
horrible explanation so many people
getting together having too
conversation about climate change they
can't really do anything because they
have 70 bucks a month and that's if they
spend all of their money but at every
level where you can see well wait there
isn't just one group of seven people
there are thousands of groups of seven
people which means you can definitely
form the old two layer which would be 49
and the old three layer which is 49
times seven roughly 350 and at each
layer you know what your budget is
because you know how much money is being
passed off to the next level and how
much money you actually have to work on
so if you get an L seven you have a ton
of money to work on climate change and
then everyone at all those levels is
voting you're keeping 25 percent of it
to spend in your group of seven as ever
you want your group of 49 your group of
roughly 350 that's one iteration that
could be used for a collaboration
platform that's both funding and it
needs to have the way for you to have
find those seven people have a
conversation with those seven people and
then form the higher-level groups and
keep feeding back into the system what's
working what's not working the point
with all of this this whole technology
cooperative is basically everything is
chicken and egg it's like well in order
to be able to collaborate on a project
you need the tools to be able to
collaborate to find the people to fund
it to put out work that you need done
right like we're talking on our project
or who we'd like next to join us right
and it's like basically anyone who wants
to but if we could pick somebody with
admin work someone who can actually I
can show up in for this conversation but
the writing out the descriptions the
writing out a lot of things they keep an
email but keeping the website going is
not my strong suit in any way so having
somebody join us that has those skill
sets if we have a collaboration platform
that's easy to find these people put in
their skill sets and you say hey people
the skill set does this project resonate
with you do you want to be part of it
and similarly if there's no one no one
within min you know degree it's like
well I'm willing to take on that role is
good enough right now right like well
I'm willing to try the admitting to try
and make a spreadsheet am willing to try
those things having a culture it isn't
about perfection it's about getting it
wrong and learning on repeat as
individuals and collectively together
until we get it right we're already
getting it wrong and
so many ways on the planet that that is
a lot of what a technology cooperative
can give us is the space to fail without
it being catastrophic
this is experiments that are safe enough
to try and so what does that look like
what does it look like to have a new
project come up and have its own funding
model and its own governance model and
have it feedback into the system what
works and what doesn't when it does fail
or when it has micro failures right like
when things go wrong they improve it
mentoring I don't know what that
question is regarding what we have
mentoring on the site it's possibly an
answer to my question if that was worth
$10 a month to you like that is
something we can do it but how much
would that then goes to the mentor
versus but the truth is a mentor might
be willing to mentor know that's kind of
cool because there's this idea like
there's people tons of people who are
willing to do work for free but there's
this when you're doing work for free
people aren't as into it as when they
pay for it so if you do counseling
you're paid 100 bucks an hour and
they're paying you $100 an hour they're
going to show up because they have to
pay you hundred dollars an hour whether
they show up or not if it's for free
they're less likely to show up and so if
people are paying $10 a month into the
system to get mentored but the mentor is
not getting because it's going to the
system the mentor is working for free
they're choosing to be there for free so
you know you're getting there like full
spirit not their paid for-profit spirit
and yet the person pain is paying for it
right so there they are showing up you
know they're both people are committed
more so than if it was you don't even I
like it I like it but I don't know what
that looks like and it this whole thing
because I'm a very non hierarchical
person or at least I want to be is I
mean if he's called it there because it
was in between safe enough to try yes
that's what a lot of this is based on my
thinking just sitting thinking about
capitalism versus communism and what
went wrong with one and what's still
going on with another and a lot of the
projects that are out there amazing but
they're not safe enough to try a debt
Jubilee is not safe enough to try
they can catastrophic ly destroy our
environment like our economy which
destroys our environment but a game that
plays a debt Jubilee safe enough to try
like a like there's things that are safe
enough to try and that's where a lot of
people want to get like a city going or
a village or a community because they
see that as a safe enough to try right
which is fine and there's nothing wrong
with that but especially when you want a
city an existing city or an existing
state or an existing country to take on
a new model to see if it works that's
already not safe enough to try like this
failing at a Canadian level or a british
columbian or a vancouver level isn't
safe enough to try whereas a company
level it is because that's kind of what
companies are designed for is to be safe
enough to try for the people involved in
creating them and a cooperative is no
different except that it brings in the
democracy piece to it it brings in more
trust to it
so having a corporation that's open and
transparent so if and when we fail
whether it's micro and we learn and grow
which is hopefully what we're doing
hopefully there isn't a catastrophic
failure but if there even if there is a
catastrophic failure you can see what
went wrong for the next iteration right
if me and Bentley have a horrible blow
up fight and it's right now so therefore
you know maybe there's no one else
involved and we split we split ways you
can see that that happens and so you
don't I mean we can see well what what
went wrong and I both Bentley and I are
not probably not going to do that and
we're probably also the type of
personalities who would at least have
another session to figure out what went
wrong there might not be those people
involved so they might never want to
talk but you I can still learn right I
can still learn and grow for those
experiences a village is safe but if we
build it a sustainable substantial
principle a substantial right I don't
know a substantial produce principle is
but it's not big right but then you need
lands right you need to be able to
follow the rules of the law and then
it's only big enough for a certain
number of people so how do you decide
who gets to live there
the people living there arts it's not
safe enough to try because it's risky
and finances right it's not free to buy
land it's not free to grow it to build
and you can do all of that much more
cheaply but no outside funder is going
to come and do it right no probably no
billionaires gonna come and be like yes
I will find your village for you so the
people creating it needs to be the ones
to fund it and it's physical and it land
is already really expensive building
materials can be pretty expensive you
don't know where and how to acquire them
and use them in that way so there's
there is risk there is risk there but if
it fails it doesn't bring down our whole
entire system so if you can find that
that finance money it's absolutely safe
enough to try and just with the
understanding that right what we're
putting in can go horrifically wrong and
are we comfortable with that right like
Bentley and I aren't putting in our
children's college education I don't
have money so my kids college education
Who am I kidding but like that's not
what's on the line here what's on the
line here is an hour of our time on
Fridays and finding people like if there
was ten thousand of us who wanted to
collaborate on creating a collaboration
platform who are willing to put in ten
thousand ten thousand dollars a month
that's all just ten thousand dollars a
month that you do to ten thousand people
willing to put in ten dollars but that's
a hundred thousand dollars we have that
we're all responsible for deciding how
that gets spent right what is the best
way to use that money to hire someone to
create a platform we don't have those
people nor we couldn't have those people
until we have a beta and so everything
is chicken-and-egg everything is like
well if we had the collaboration
platform I wouldn't need to create the
collaboration platform I would just be
starting projects and going on and
seeing if people were interested in them
if we had the communication platform we
wouldn't need to create it I would just
be on here having conversations with
everyone and but once we have that once
we have a basic collaboration tool it
unlocks everything because then isn't
just our collective that's moving
forward it's anyone with an idea for a
project what we're doing for a project
raising on Saturdays is one hour of our
time
we can only have up to five people on
video people can watch and participate
as well but there's a real barrier right
like you can't afford them by people
playing you can only have one project at
a time and it's only one hour a week if
there's a platform design for that or
you can bring any idea at any stage to
to the collective and they can help
improve it they could help fund it if
there's enough if there's enough um
what's wanting to fund it puzzle and put
follow it is a matter of finding the
right combination of people that can
work synergistically who will for 10
euros per month yes no no there's
there's ways to do it I'm just saying
that there's not like um if they're not
living there right they're not living at
the village so they're just funding it
why are they funding yours over theirs
right like why they might be just a
philanthropist that's ready to like give
out like hey we're gonna start ten
communities and see which one of them is
safe enough right like that's safe
enough for them because they have the
money it's not a huge risk of how the
one I have a coffin I must still be
talking a lot it is the one they're
gonna have to talk to the entire hour
like they probably have a vision of what
you have a vision right of what your
village looks like what your community
looks like there's gonna be things that
you're willing to compromise on and
things you're not willing to compromise
on they're gonna want the things they
are not willing to compromise on in a
village right even if they're not living
there with the idea they might live
there someday and so they're gonna put
stipulations probably on the money given
right unless they're not if there's
someone out there who's just like hey I
want to find ten people who have a
vision for a village and let them run
run amok and you don't I mean like
everyone have 50 people and then you
come together and co-create what that
looks like which is also it needs to get
done for there to be a in my in my
experience and effective
I think intentional community you need a
community of people to have the
conversation on what that looks like
not one person starting one and then
have
everyone joined them but having a
conversation that's how the coal housing
community I'm part of got started it's
why it actually works because the people
there knew we wanted to have collective
meals and they were a rather big
priority so nobody who didn't most of
the people who are participating are
people who want to be part of the
collective meals there's other things
that have come up since that of like the
play area and the woodworking thing and
all these things that are that like our
values come into conflict but and like
do how many times to eat meatless in a
week how many times we do is there
always a vegan option is there always a
gluten-free option like there's still
conflict around the food but the people
are there to be an intentional community
right to co-create what that looks like
not me like not a vegan a vegan could
start to be like I only want to do this
with vegan people and there would be
less conflict around the vegan s but not
necessarily the rest of it a problem to
be solved you're wanting to solve some
of the immigration issues issue
yeah and that's I mean you have your own
vision for what and why you want to
create right and to be able to have a
platform to be able to have that
conversation on to say I mean there's
I've been looking for it involved with
intentional communities for I would say
at least a decade now I have a book on
like finding them and there's ones that
are you know around a religion they're
ones that are around for more living off
the land and ones that are not like are
you sharing money once where you don't
share in money in one's firm the
cohousing that I'm part of is amazing it
also has some drawbacks you own a house
there so you've got both entices you to
deal with conflict resolution because
these are your neighbors you're gonna be
living with them for decades but also if
someone stops a level of conflict that
needs to happen to get there because
these are your neighbors what if we hate
each other we can't get into that like
what if there is some kind of
head-butting
having an online community like game be
for me a little bit isn't safe enough to
fail for me personally I'm like I really
like it I really want it to exist I
really like having a community to go to
who I can talk about these things
because before the
I was just alienate everyone in my life
talking about them but if it went away I
now know what it could look like and
could may be more likely to recreate it
then before before it gave me existed
before I had the language before when I
was still in gay because that's what
I've been doing this for like four years
now creating what I was talking about
dismantling capitalism I only heard
about game be it September 13th I guess
is a big part helping people to find
meaningful work synergistically is huge
and that to me is what a technology
cooperative can do because not that not
that a village can't because that is
also like saying hey do you want to come
work off the land that's gonna draw in
people who want to do whatever work is
there to do but having a tool a
technology tool that can help you figure
out who are you what are your skills
what are your strengths what are your
weaknesses what are your challenges and
help you find people to that what does
work together well synergistically I
guess and it's you know like instead of
going on being like well hey you group
of people you you're poor and you're
starving so you have to come and work
this land to me isn't necessarily a
solution but having people being part of
hey what if you won the lottery what do
you want to do what would you spend your
time doing if we lived in a world where
you didn't have to help other people
because everyone could help themselves
what do you spend your time doing and
then co-creating solutions that actually
look like that that actually look like
how do you live your best life how do I
live my best life and what does that
look like what does our food system look
like our clothing system look like that
isn't its current iteration and isn't I
get to dictate what it looks like for
everyone like where the the options are
diverse but the system that makes it
efficient is one system so the
information and the people are in one
spot but the options to be involved are
infinite or nearly infinite someone has
to come up with one for it to be added
but the potential of someone coming up
with one is infinite
I was just before this morning I I'm not
gonna butcher his name if he if I say it
one of the people in game B had put up a
like how many slaves work for you
website which didn't work when I first
clicked on it but this morning it
actually did work so I clicked on an
i-32 slaves working for me the issue
with a lot of those things are one you
have to know that that website exists to
go there and use it but even once that
it doesn't tell me how to not use those
slaves it doesn't give me another option
my options what use the like farmers
market for my food great that's not
actually ethnic oh yeah many of those
people use migrant workers and they pay
next to nothing like that's not
necessarily ethical and I can't afford
it so like there has to be a solution we
can find for feeding ourselves that
isn't relying on other people's labor
that isn't relying on but it's starting
from where we are it's starting from
where do I currently get my food and how
do i improve it how do I look at the
truth of where my food comes from and
make it better and I can't do it by
myself
you need organic doing those things are
only kind of available to the rich even
gardening isn't really accessible to me
being part of coho zena's where they
have a garden and I help sometimes and
you know we go and pick the food and
there's some people who are very
involved in that and my contribution is
I sweep the yoga studio every two weeks
but it's not like I there's parts of be
involved in that community that are
somewhat a rule right everyone who's
who's able to who's an adult
participates in cleaning and cooking
once a cycle which is roughly once a
month
there's also pieces that are completely
optional like I wanted to contribute
more I don't live there so I don't
really have to contribute but I wanted
to contribute more so sweeping the yoga
studio is within my physical capacity
and it makes me feel good I'm like yes I
want to do that there's people who like
are retired and spend 30 hours a week
dealing with the compost like that's
their passion and they are we know
they're the compost person someone else
like the recycling person and sometimes
there's things that fall through the
cracks or those
people need help but there needs to be a
way to ask for it in a way that's like
yes this is my passion but I don't want
to be doing it thirty hours a week I
want to be doing it ten hours a week
where two more people who want to be
guided by me being like the leader of
the compost and those things can all be
made more efficient and easier with
technology because some of us don't have
a community that we can just tap into we
can just go to and work for these things
it's probably clearly just gonna be
riding my bumper for an hour this is old
school who said I was doing back in
September although I feel a little
better at it than I was then so that's
good
it's kind of nice to come back home and
see that like see that the pieces that
have changed this idea that in game B
there's this two factions it's what
split up the last game B of people who
are like we need to get done we
need to actually do things our world is
burning and people who are like right we
need people with the capacity to do that
so we need to do the interpersonal work
right we need to like actually um get to
the point we can work with other people
and it's not step one and then step two
it's like both of those things have to
happen and there's people working in one
and not in the other one and that's fine
if people working in the other one or
not that one but we need people to
Bridgette and tools help us do both we
as a group are trying to practice a mega
rule but there are things that are make
a rule like that aren't so make a rule
that all we're also trying to practice
like nonviolent communication and
circling and things that are tools we
use that aren't mandatory no one has to
do circle you know in half Sydney
nonviolent communication in fact even
Omega roll is supposed to be somewhat of
an invitation instead of a forced this
is out this how it goes what's my name
is Sergey the it'd the personal work
right meditation certain and the group
work like circling are both things that
people can do to improve themselves by
invitation so if we have a platform that
helps you find that if you're having an
issue with an
Jen here are some tools you could use
whichever ones work for you great which
are there is no one tool you're having
an issue with anger here's ways people
deal with anger here's this person's you
know too old here's this person's tool
people like you would have found this
tool works better free for them the
interpersonal work of like finding
people to practice so make a rule with
which is what I'm doing on Wednesdays I
did was not the one to instigate that
group but it is very much a big part of
what I am doing in game be it's like
okay I have the idea cafe
you'll make a rule all of my
contributions are just conversations
because that is what I'm capable of is
showing up and having a conversation
it's like the idea Cafe is a
conversation that I'm hosting when other
people come enjoy and he'll make a rule
as a conversation Eric posts and that's
awesome and we pick a new topic every
week and we try to like find the thing
in the conversation this last week was
on goodness and it was amazing
and everyone who wants to can have
access if it can have access to that
group we have a limit
Friday we can't we just invited another
person like there's like so many people
we can have there and when people
consistently don't show up we can add
more people but we can't just put it out
to game be and like view it kind of like
I do at the idea cafe and see hey
whoever shows up shows up because
they'll be too many people on the zoom
call and nobody will get a chance to
speak and how do we pick a topic and all
of that stuff be not my point that that
isn't it's already anti-bible risks like
people practicing the omega rule in
groups choosing to do it isn't dictate
and everyone else has to do and it's
also not stopping them from doing it and
we're Bentley and I with together tech
looking to create the tools that make it
even easier to be part of a conversation
because not everyone is comfortable
having a conversation live on YouTube or
broadcast on YouTube after but this is
we're doing it this way because we want
people to come and hear about it and
come on board and we want to be
transparent later on
more of us we won't necessarily need to
be live on YouTube our board meeting if
we solve a board meeting has to be live
on YouTube because our membership
potential and actual need to be able to
see it but once we have enough people we
have actual membership instead of just
potential membership we only need to be
live and transparent in them in which
case and then we need to also listen to
them as to what's comfortable and not
comfortable for them so if we hold itea
cafes not live on YouTube that was never
the idea the idea of an idea cafe is
that it follows the world cafe model and
people participate in small intimate
conversations multiple times the same
conversation or a lead on conversation
with different people so the larger
group is also having a conversation
that's not really what showcased on the
YouTube channel because it just me or
yeah I'm part of every conversation me
having a conversation with can be people
around the meeting for question every
week and we do it kinda we don't do it
live we vote on it afterwards and do it
unlisted and then because it's not about
people comments you like it is here it's
about actually us having a conversation
not everyone's comfortable with that
there's this a lot of like issues in the
marketing that we've talked about of
introverts who participated in it find
it very meaningful they enjoy that
process it's in fact almost tailor-made
for introverts
but having it live on YouTube not
tailor-made for introverts and most
introverts don't know they want to be
part of it until they've been part of it
and tried a bit like oh yeah I liked
that that was not confrontational that
wasn't the same way that I've
experienced other group conversations
and so a lot of what we're solving
in-game be and all the projects our
problems people don't know they have and
so marketing comes into play
huge many projects especially in the
tech place that is their their thing
that falls through is they just don't
have the right people on board at the
right time so you needed 10,000 people
to have a threshold for it to be
actually usable like Wikipedia is
awesome it wouldn't have went anywhere
if there weren't enough people to put in
to put in content and to read it
and therefore propagated and therefore
we started believing it and more people
came in and did that a lot of these
things are a snowball right once it
starts and starts rolling downhill it
grows and rose and grows and grows but
it has to start and if we can create the
platform that's the snowball starter for
all projects because it's yes if you're
actually solving a problem for people we
want them to know about it as a person
who has problems I want to know if you
have a solution to it even if I haven't
thought about that problem with our
collaboration platform once it's
actually a collaboration platform I'm
sure we will be concentrating on issues
that are important to most of us like
food like health care things that are
nearly universal we all need them but
there will also be niche groups that are
like for me my disability comes into
play a lot regular everyday able-bodied
people aren't necessarily gonna be part
of that conversation because they're not
even gonna see it they're not even going
to read but the things we come up with
in that space having those conversations
for like what tools we make for the
neuro-diverse book tools for people who
have brain damage which rules can we
make for people who don't have enough
energy those tools will also help people
who didn't know they had energy problems
who didn't know they had memory problems
who didn't know that that these things
could exist because they because the
world was working well enough for them
but in order for it to work for the
truly deeply needed those people with
chronic brain injury those people with
autism and ATD in order for them to be
able to utilize it like a group of
people has to come together to make it
right so ideally that would be a bunch
of neurodiverse people but how do you
get them there to have that conversation
and so a collaboration platform can
solve that piece because it's like who
do you need to talk to in your a case
Khali if you're looking to create a
village you might want to talk to a
bunch of people who've already lived in
one right to ask them your questions and
all you're doing is putting out that
question and people are seeing whether
or not they want to come on board right
now good luck with that that's what I do
all the time if you put that out on
Twitter or even in the game be space you
might have two or three people be part
of a conversation but it's not going to
be a thousand people who come be part of
a conversation but there's enough people
I know who've lived an intentional
who if I was able to target them
specifically and they put it on their
Facebook group you would automatically
get those in that group of people
because it's it's you know what I mean
it's more targeted it's not Facebook
targeting them it's me worm calling them
being like hey this person wants to find
out about intentional communities like I
know one of the architects who helped
create the cohousing
and wrote the book on cohousing I don't
know if he would be interested to be
part of a video conversation but like
those kind of that's my point
how mean one collaboration space where
people are so that you can who want to
need listen they want to help right so
they want to say hey here's my skill set
if I can help you move forward great and
like right now in this facing game be in
all spaces we're all very highly
triggered by other people not doing the
work we've already done and people doing
the work we've already done like all of
it all of it is triggering we all
project we all do these these things and
to be able like if I don't want to do
something I imagine nobody wants to do
it but that's not true
what I was talking to people about the
idea before it was ever kind of together
tech and how we find people find
synergistic work I was like you know
like everyone has a genius and everyone
has passion and we want them to be
working in that passion and there's some
things that like nobody wants to do like
cleaning toilets the first person I used
that analogy with she was like I like
cleaning toilets I was like you just
broke it all I'm like why why do you
like cleaning toilets and I was like I
don't like cleaning toilets I would not
like thinking other people's toilets but
I would be okay making beds like even
though I don't like making my own bed if
I if that was the one thing I did and I
just went down the block and made
everyone's done for the week okay I
guess I'd do that and I'm not saying
that's the solutions were creating I
don't know if we want to piecemeal art
or house work and then how people come
in and out of our house it's doing it
but to have the platform to be able to
have an idea and have people jump on
board and workshop it is what would be
amazing
starting with production cooperatives
and creating meaningful and synergistic
work production cooperatives what do you
mean by a production cooperative because
I like I know cooperatives and there's
generally like three types of the fourth
one emerging which were kind of the
fourth one is worker cooperatives
consumer cooperatives or producer
cooperatives so producer cooperatives is
like Ocean Spray where all the cranberry
farmers are like part of it and so
that's a cooperative even though they're
still on the market it's not benefiting
me that they were cooperative we're a
cooperative my friends in the in the
woodshop cooperative they're part
they're not even carpenters people who
like working with wood we're creating
wood and they're they're setting their
own wage and they're finding their own
work and they're doing within this
cooperative credit unions and Mountain
Equipment co-op are consumer
cooperatives where it's good person
buying the good that is the membership
that they care about there's also a new
emergent cooperative called a platform
cooperative which is basically any of
those that facilitated by an online
platform so if Facebook was a
cooperative it would be like the people
who are using us the people where the
ownership it would be a member of
coopera it would be like that's where
platform isn't its own thing because the
ones that exist right now I can never
remember it there's a photography one
there's a photography platform that is a
cooperative and the photographer's the
ones that are members so it's basically
a worker cooperative so finding so I
don't know what you mean by production
cooperative like whether that's like the
people needing the product are they the
ones collaborating or the people making
the products there's also hybrids of but
there are also generally needs to be
like an overarching to some degree which
one's the bigger piece like van City is
a great place to work but it is not a
worker cooperative you have to be a
member to work there but you're a member
of the credit union
you're not mech is the same thing like
the workers it's a good place to work
they have good benefits that gave them
well but they're not a worker
cooperative
similarly the woodwork the wood shop is
that's a cooperative
has really good pricing like that's part
of their model is that they want to be
able to give people good wood objects at
not an ikea price but not a high-end
price either and have it be specially
made so they're not pricing them at the
high-end even though they possibly could
because they're amazing
they're pricing them at the midpoint so
generally one comes into play and the
other one but not so I don't know what
you mean by production cooperative
unless you are talking about like Ocean
Spray like it's just my own personal
bias those funds is like in the
co-operative meetings like the BC
co-operative ones I'm like and the
producer one's like what are they even
here for like I don't they're not I
don't care when I go to a grocery store
I don't care that it's the dairy
co-operative
I care about mom-and-pop dairies a
mom-and-pop farms and I want to help
them but when you get together become a
cooperative aren't you now just a new
cool all right issues more production so
the village okay so the village itself
is producing goods that are being sold
and those things sold the profit goes to
like the entire village is that the
basic concept so it's like a that is
kind of a new type of cooperative like
it's kind of like a and yet not cuz like
the Amish the Hutterites
all of them like already do that but
it's not the it's dinner wouldn't call
it a cooperative like that's not like
it's both been here since the beginning
of time since we started having villages
and working together like every tribe
ever was basically that right you work
together to and you share in the balance
you create together but yeah all right
an incubator of generative businesses
holistic health generative agriculture
I'm definitely interested in hearing
more because I have tons of questions on
how that would how that would work
incubator
incubator for regenerative businesses
because those that's important but like
who who decides that what it is where
does the funding come where it is like
all the same issues were dealing with
right here of like the tech cooperative
because my first iteration which was not
a tech Robert and but it had tech in it
I was like we're gonna recreate the
entire means of production we were going
to because a cooperative that's designed
for purpose instead of profit can take
over every industry when it's
transparent and democratic where I get
to choose whether or not I use it but I
also get to have a say in what makes it
better and help improve it then it
doesn't matter where it starts it
generally becomes better than whatever
is currently out there wasn't part of
that oh and then we went back to tech
like I was like tech is where we start
because you need the tech to do anything
else and technology is already on me
when like if you're creating tables and
somebody comes to you and says I would
love your table but I don't have enough
money to pay for it
there are ways you can help them right
you can help them do the woodworking you
know they can trade labor for it there's
other issues or other solutions but
there's still a cost to that table a
real cost that you know they have to put
in or you someone else has to put in and
give it to them whereas the technology
most of the cost comes at like third
there's there's ongoing costs like
servers but it's on a per person thing
it's like someone else coming on board
might cost pennies but they generate
dollars and they bring with them omni
wind solutions they bring with them
their purpose their passion their genius
their challenges their you know like
they bring with them all of that and so
every new person that comes on board is
a win for everybody like right now our
third person coming on board with
Bentley and I will be like right now our
used to be just me you know it's like
50/50 it'll be like 33 3333 it's not
it's not like real ownership where it's
like the next person comes on board
brings it to 25 if that was actual
ownership every person dilutes our
potential but it's not that it's like
the work that needs to get done a
hundred percent Bentley and I okay well
and we're never going to do 50/50 this
is a thing that needs to have dozens
hundreds of people having conversations
and there will naturally be people
arise with you the 80 person the 20
percentage of the 80% but more people
coming on board doesn't cost us it gives
to us and that's why it's great it does
need to rebuild the entire system yes we
do need to rebuild the entire entire
system and yet it's that's like a
colossal thing to do and so there had
happened in my opinion it needs from the
individual themselves it has to be fun
to do it has to give them something for
me that's it being fun and easy because
if it's enjoyable and I'm having a blast
doing game B and doing all of this stuff
even this where wooden Bentley was like
I'm not gonna make it tomorrow I was
like maybe we'll move it it was like
that doesn't really work because you
want people knowing that we're at 11
a.m. and I was hoping other people would
come on board to be on video because
that is what we're looking to do maybe
this forward is having guest speakers
the one so like guest bored me members
they aren't taking ownership they don't
need to take on 33% of the work and be
the third board member they're just
offering their opinions and ideas during
that conversation itself oh I'm paying
the price for talking for an hour later
but sitting here in silence it's not
gonna work so up so we're looking for
like what we're looking to collaborate
on a collaboration platform that is all
and everything but there's only two of
us two people can't collaborate you
don't a collaboration platform so we
need more people to come and be part of
the conversation to say what works for
them in collaboration what like for me
part of what I'm working with is most of
my ideas most of this save-the-world
cooperative stuff has been me alone in
my bedroom coming up with stuff on paper
because I enjoy it it's fun it's fun for
me to do that nothing gets done there I
have to be able to bring it out into the
world for something to actually get done
and so now with the game be space I'm
like learning how to work in a group in
a different way where I'm like I still
don't know how to actually generate an
idea together I don't have a
conversation and I know how to generate
90 go by myself but like any word that
you kind of line up
and and that's what kind of conversation
leads to their and that's what the idea
Cafe is one of the things that is an
idea on how to do that and there's other
ways like the fishbowl that are it's a
fishbowl dialogue circle which I would
also liked it to talk about not right
now
but there's different ways to have a
conversation where the individual has is
able to be heard and less than two by a
small group of people because you can't
do that in a large group but the larger
group is having a conversation it is
effective so we're talking you know in
tiny groups about problem solving and
generating ideas and and what's our
obstacle personally and collectively the
best ideas are able to be so be funneled
up right and what up means I don't know
if there's no hierarchy but that more of
us hear about it right so we're having a
conversation with with just four of us
and someone comes up with it with an
amazing idea how do how does it get out
there and then later when we when
someone did come up with amazing idea
but it never got out there why didn't it
right so so there's a lot of times in
history where like 9/11 happens and then
there are people or let's not go back
quite that far Trump got elected and
then there were people who are like I
knew Trump was gonna get elected look
like Michael Moore is like I told you
guys we were like he's think he wanted
Trump elected I'm like that's not quite
the same thing he just said he would get
elected so there's the financial
collapse and people who most economists
aren't great at predicting what the
economy does cuz the economy is really
complicated but there were some there
were like look subprime mortgage it's
about to collapse they're not
necessarily going to be the next ones to
know the next thing is coming but
they're better than the people who just
thought it was gonna chug along fine and
so looking back at who did have an idea
that would have helped this and how I
work there why wasn't their idea brought
forward now if they just didn't say it
then we need to ask well why didn't you
say it at the time right like what would
have made you feel more safe to say it
as it was said and other people didn't
hear it or didn't you know upload it why
what was what was that part of it like
we need to come up with a system to be
able to work together on a massive
ille to be able to understand the issues
have access to the information we need
to solve the problems even if the rest
of the world doesn't care about that
information we want to access that
information so if we're working on
climate change you want to be able to
understand the science and understand
what is true and what is into where as
carbon coming from and what other toxins
are out there and what is what is their
part in the ecosystem in a way we
actually understand it not so
climatologist can have this conversation
but so climate deniers can have this
conversation right like for that
specific category we would want climate
deniers to be part of that conversation
not let's debate the climate science but
like what would we want to be answered
what would it look like if humans were
and conferred the cause of climate
change would it look like if we weren't
even if we aren't how do we best
mitigate this right like having the
conversation without the debate like
taking it away from the debate and
finding like right where's the science
is there what is missing from the
science what is every question we would
want to answer an answer for climate
change which ones have been answered who
funded them why are they you know like
look at the actual actual bigger bigger
picture of the question to be able to do
any of that we need to have our own
collaboration platform we need to be
able to look at who wants to be involved
in this conversation do we have enough
people to be involved in this
conversation how do we run that
conversation and that's where we're not
discussing climate change we're not
discussing food scarcity we're not
discussing those things or discussing
how we break like how do you create the
thing that helps facilitate all of that
so that when something happens like the
iran-us es that's going on right now
it's like new war that's starting i've
had like ten ideas between then and now
and on things that could bring us closer
together are any of them the answer
maybe not but like if there was a space
I could bring it to and all the people
who care about that issue because based
on social media nearly everyone cares
about that issue even if it's not the
way I agree with them they are care
about it so to be able to say okay well
how do we not have more it's just a
conversation I want to have even if
whatever the other side might want more
um there is not like that is the other
side
or you don't want more those to me are
the sides not the argue every Iranian or
America and it's like do you want words
you know or and how can the people who
don't want war how can we actually
facilitate when we have no power to
actually stop war how do we actually
create the tools to be able to track the
money to be able to track the Killians
to be able to see when it's true what is
happening what is happening on the
ground who's responsible it's not the
Iranian people right it's not like they
didn't get together and vote to bomb
that airplane if they got bombed they
didn't get together just like the
Americans didn't get together and vote
to assassinate the guy writing like that
didn't happen but it's them who's gonna
pay the price it's like the American
soldier and all of the Iranian people if
they go to war and maybe the American
public if things reach this far I don't
know there are four Canadians as well
I don't want war I want to be able to
solve it but there's this like
underlining conversation that people
don't eat it's like well we have to
tackle climate change we have to go up
straws we all have to it's like that's
not actually the solution the solution
is meeting people where they are why are
people using straws why are people using
gee gocubs why are people doing this and
then how do we recreate a lifestyle for
them that they can feel good about that
doesn't do that and meet them where they
are like what would get you not to use a
straw demanding everyone doesn't use
straws as ablest as because people
need straws some people really need
straws it's like well then you can use
this kind ask them if they can use that
kind why could you were couldn't you use
a metal one or a silicone one or a paper
one and help them create a solution it
actually facilitates the like outcome of
no more straws or no more useless
because I don't want to stain my
lipstick straws and that's also
important what if what you don't like
whatever going for a job interview and
you don't want your lipstick and your
kids are starving at home it's like
alright that's a different other than
thing Thank You Colleen thank you for
coming and hanging out and asking
questions and we'll be on for like three
more minutes then I'm gonna go this was
a nice little Friday flashback of what
it was like when I was all by myself
in September answering questions on the
and now not I'm not on one myself
both Bentley but also you guys you guys
are here listening and asking questions
my guess is most of you are from game B
which came into contact with and
figuring out hey Matt nice nice yeah no
it takes that I don't know if I've
participated in a live chat on somebody
else's no yeah I have on future thinkers
I have um but co-creating something I
mean I'm a very stubborn person I have
my own ideas and I don't necessarily
Bend on them in my own way like I'm not
even someone's not gonna be able to come
in and make me become approach pro-life
or pro-choice so it's not going to come
in and be able to make me right wake
when I'm left-wing but I see the beauty
of diversity I see that we need people
who are both left-wing and right-wing we
all send in people who are who are anti
choice and you know pro-choice or anti
life and pro-life whichever side you're
on we need to find a way to work
together without getting along because
step one's not gonna be we all get along
it's not like that's not a stuff we're
not gonna all get along so how do we
work together without getting along how
do we actually have the outcomes we need
how do we actually create the tech that
helps us get along more and part of its
segregation a little bit right if you
can't get along you guys don't need to
be at the same table if you're willing
to not get along and learn from each
other that would be really great but if
you're not then you guys need to split
up and I'll be together because you're
wrecking it for everyone else right your
your yeah and what was that point the
other piece of that technology you're
not getting along I don't remember to
find the piece that we do get along with
I guess to find what the conversation is
like a little bit of conflict that's
been in the game be space recently we
all want game B we disagree with how to
get there we disagree with the
priorities of how to get there we all
have our own work to work on we all have
like I care deeply about racism and
about poverty however poverty is a
little bit of my place to play in
because I'm in poverty in my in my
country but I'm not in poverty in India
and Pakistan right like those are
completely different worlds and I'm also
an
white person in poverty here which I
know comes a privilege but I am a
disabled queer person single mom like
I'm a lot of things that are I can speak
to those things and I want to find other
people like this top down I need someone
to else to come in and solve my problems
I don't want and I also I can't solve
them on my own
it had there has to be a coordinated
effort of where do I find other single
moms to coordinate with how do we help
facilitate people in a small village in
Zimbabwe coming together and solving
their own energy food whatever problems
without you know someone coming in and
and and saving it for them because
that's not if it's just not effective
and it comes with a lot of historical
context instead of what would help how
can we help you and every step every
good thing that's out there right now
can be better facilitated with better
tech and more coordinated technology not
the blockchain which I've printed on
about well with this power there there's
beauty and power in the blockchain but
you can't turn everything into a nail in
order to apply a hammer and blockchain
doesn't include most people it doesn't
include intellectually most people
technologically most people like people
don't understand it you can't implant a
system that people don't understand when
it's it's taking over from a system and
maybe people don't understand what they
understood the beginning and then it was
on top of it whatever I'll just get on
my oh my normal rants all right so I've
been here an hour I shouldn't be talking
anymore I should have been talking for
that hour but we do this every it's
usually that lee and i working on
creating the technology cooperative we
use this hour to move it forward to see
what items we want to take on talk about
new ideas we also have both of us this
new project raising on saturday mornings
with my brother who isn't game b but his
project is very game b we rose we raised
we raised his project last week wiki
elections wiki lecture and i cant even s
on it
this week we are raising oh and i forgot
his first name cousins second names
coming and not the first one o j cousins
is that right hmm I'm gonna say J
cousins
and his project which is all being home
and they'll be racing that's more money
the idea is when we bring other people's
projects on we help them for an hour do
whatever we can whatever their
aspiration is to move forward what
should come next well depends what
people want to come next I mean that's
very like Bentley and I are running this
thing unless other people come on board
right like we're the ones steering eggs
really ones on video showing up every
week although there's people who are
showing up in the comments every week
and that as much appreciated and once
there's a way for people to actually
become members those people are full
members you don't have to appear on
camera in order to be to be a full
member is that's not comfortable for
everyone you do have to be a real person
we have to figure that out right how do
we know you're a real person and you
have one account but which kids
ironically figured out by a blockchain
watching people do that oh um what is
next is like we're meeting to talk about
how we create a beta something that is
useful that people want how do we fund
it how do we do that right now that's
looking to create a platform that's like
the idea Cafe that's coordinating that
it's coordinating he made a way to give
it yeah and there will be we're actually
looking we're talking about we just
talked about it in the very brief board
meeting that we had yesterday and I
published to talk about this one if they
have not showing up maybe like what do
we do let's find other people and we're
looking to get our project together tech
on github then we need a hundred people
to like it in order to be able to use
their um program to or another person's
program to probably knows the names of
all these things to him and I can put
money in and then collectively we decide
where it goes right so if a third person
comes on board they're also putting
their money in then we're collectively
just I know it goes so they have the
software to be able to do that but never
be able to use that software you have to
have an open-source technology ours is
open source it's open everything um and
part of that is before they allow you to
do that you need a hundred likes on
github which means you be part of github
and so we will need people to do that
that's probably
all end up talking about next week we're
also looking to like I said change this
to be a little less Bentley and I
talking and a little more a third person
coming and helping us problem-solve the
next the next one and that probably will
mean we need to figure out what the like
everything we need to solve to get that
first project out there and then having
people come and work on pieces of it for
us right like the funding the legal the
whatever it is having guests that are
willing to be part of it for that hour
not taking on responsibility long term
so thank you for hanging out and I'm
gonna go and rest my voice before I have
people over tonight and clean my house
so thank you and we do this I keep
started saying the same thing over ever
done we do this every Friday at this
time so like an hour and five minutes
ago is when we start we're on for an
hour and we're discussing how to move
the technology cooperative forward the
point is this is our technology company
what does it need for you to want to
collaborate what does it need to be for
we're not gonna make it for you right
like I'm not gonna like take on the job
of making something that works for
somebody else but you get to come be
part of making it work for you you get
to come be part of all that's not going
to work because or I wouldn't fund that
because like we're all in it together
and we're all creating something and
that awesome that I'm glad you're in and
you can contact me on well email game be
space on Facebook Twitter and talk about
what that means to all the hbn I'm
thinking I haven't run this by Bentley
but like I said people can come be
guests for members for the week and if
they show up on video like three times I
want to continue to be part of it and
that's when they can kind of like be a
board member because then they showed up
three weeks not in a row but total then
that shows that they're more committed
whereas people will come one time you
like yeah and then and then they won't
keep coming just fine life gets in the
way things change but if we're counting
on something to be a third board member
and then they're not the third board
member that isn't really you know work
so I'm excited to move this forward in
2020 it's so funny how the more I let go
of what it's supposed to look like the
faster it happens it's like right I
can't have it be my way it's gonna be
our way we're gonna figure out what
collaboration looks like how do we have
conversations it's really
easy when there's under six of us
because it's live here at 11 a.m.
once we get to the seventh person we are
gonna have to figure out well how are
you rotating are we figuring it out
because we want to create something that
works for people who want to create a
technology company a collaboration
platform and so there'll be a lot of
talking listening awesome thanks Matt
and I will see you all well
Torro for the project raising and then
also idea cafe on the other channel and
the other this one next week I'll be 40
by then I have a birthday on Tuesday so
happy birthday to me I think I will see
you all next week
thanks for hanging up